<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My thoughts and adventures</title>
    <link>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My thoughts and adventures</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyleft; Feel free to steal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 09:14:08 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Add a custom titlebar to your nw.js app</title>
      <link>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/custom_titlebar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 09:14:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/custom_titlebar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I am going to show you how to create a custom titlebar for your nw.js app. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of nw.js, check it out
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nwjs/nw.js&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It enables a new way of writing desktop applications with all web technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s answer a simple question. &lt;strong&gt;Why do we need a custom titlebar ?&lt;/strong&gt; Because it&amp;rsquo;s better than the default one and it looks
the &lt;strong&gt;same across different platforms&lt;/strong&gt;. Default titlebar looks different, on different operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Devlog with custom titlebar&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/images/custom_titlebar/custom titlebar.png&#34; alt=&#34;custom titlebar&#34; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;And with default one.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/images/custom_titlebar/default titlebar.png&#34; alt=&#34;default titlebar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Custom titlebar looks cool right ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first thing we do is, we disable the default titlebar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;window&amp;quot;: {
  &amp;quot;toolbar&amp;quot;: false,
  &amp;quot;frame&amp;quot;: false
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that, make the &lt;strong&gt;frame&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;toolbar&lt;/strong&gt; name false in package.json. This will remove the frame, and now the window becomes
frameless.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the first step, we will notice that the window is frameless now and we will not be able to drag the
application anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the whole window draggable, add style &lt;code&gt;-webkit-app-region: drag&lt;/code&gt; to body tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body style=&amp;quot;-webkit-app-region: drag&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    ...
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or we can make a particular region draggable, by adding style &lt;code&gt;-webkit-app-region: drag&lt;/code&gt; to that element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div class=&amp;quot;titlebar&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;-webkit-app-region: drag&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    ...
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, our application is draggable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next thing, we add the window buttons (close, minimize and maximize)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For buttons, I&amp;rsquo;ve used semantic-ui &lt;a href=&#34;http://semantic-ui.com/elements/label.html#circular&#34;&gt;labels&lt;/a&gt; for devlog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OS X style buttons&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/images/custom_titlebar/window buttons.png&#34; alt=&#34;Alt text&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it&amp;rsquo;s not perfect, it does the job well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it, we have successfully created a custom titlebar for our nw.js application. Go ahead and create awesome titlebars for your apps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little about myself</title>
      <link>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 21:48:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/myself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a self taught programmer. It started out as a journey to explore the world of computers, the digital world. I started off with the fundamentals. I can say that my entire learning was a fruit of all the questions I’ve asked myself. Questions, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Like how internet works ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I started programming just to answer this question &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How does a c program make a computer do some work?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In schools and colleges they’ve always taught us how to write c program in an editor, then compile and run. But I wasn’t able to connect the dots. How could this be making a computer work? I used to think. I found the answer to this. It was &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Borland_Turbo_C&#34;&gt;Turbo C&lt;/a&gt;, which by providing user friendliness was hiding something. Only after I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://gcc.gnu.org/&#34;&gt;gcc&lt;/a&gt;, I understood the process. There can be two sides, one is user friendliness and the other is transparency. Take the example of windows and linux, windows is user friendly but hides a lot about what’s happening inside. But linux is very transparent in terms of what is happening. You can see the code for yourself. This is one of the reason’s that made me believe “ok C program can make computer do things”. I never said no to anything related to computer after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with GUI programming in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gtk.org/&#34;&gt;GTK&lt;/a&gt;. No wonder I started with GUI, as I was a windows user back then. After a couple of months I replaced windows with ubuntu. Using linux was very different. It gave me the feeling of a hacker. Typing commands in console, I felt like, I am actually interacting with the computer. Suddenly I felt empowered. I started learning about networking. Wireshark, tcpdump, airmon-ng using these tools I got to know what happens behind the scene. So I learnt some things about networking, which previously, I took for granted.
One day when I was using this tool &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secdev.org/projects/scapy/&#34;&gt;scapy&lt;/a&gt;, I got very much interested in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/&#34;&gt;python&lt;/a&gt;. So I started learning it. The name was also very cool. It was very easy to learn. I opened &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/2/&#34;&gt;official docs&lt;/a&gt; in browser and in terminal I opened python, and started typing commands. Actually I was programming Interactively. Then I started out with Interview Street. It is a platform where you can solve programming challenges. It was fascinating. Later Interview Street became &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hackerrank.com/&#34;&gt;Hackerrank&lt;/a&gt;. By solving those challenges, I got better at the way I think. I still solve challenges in Hackerrank. It’s good for my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got to know about &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34;&gt;git&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. It was intriguing, to know how github works. Distributed collaboration using git, remarkable.
Open source is a world that is always special to me.
All I understood was that I can learn things fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother was doing MBA in Information security. So I got to know about Nmap, Netcat, snort, nessus, rainbow tables etc. I also configured snort in my laptop. I also wrote a simple plugin for nessus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming made me confident, I have gone through one of the toughest times in my life without a lot of pain because of programming.
It was so addictive. I was very much in love with it, so much that I wasn’t thinking of anything else. It made me believe that I can do things.
Actual things that can be useful to others. Above all, it makes me very happy. It changed the way I think. I started to approach things in an efficient way, Thanks to programming.
I am very grateful to the community. I have never seen anything like this before. Great pioneers are part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional programming in python</title>
      <link>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/functional_programming_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 16:46:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/functional_programming_python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python offers some good functions to the developers to write functional like code. But their use is not
recommended as it reduces code readability. They may come handy in some places though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an example program showing the use of functional concepts in python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;T = input()

pi = &amp;quot;31415926535897932384626433833&amp;quot;

def calculate(song):
      words = map(lambda x: str(len(x)), song.split(&amp;quot; &amp;quot;))
      p = reduce(lambda a, b: a + b, words)

      if(p == pi[:len(p)]):
          print &amp;quot;It&#39;s a pi song.&amp;quot;
      else:
          print &amp;quot;It&#39;s not a pi song.&amp;quot;


for _ in range(T):
    song = raw_input()
    calculate(song)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to hugo</title>
      <link>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:09:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Migrating to hugo based blog. I am super exited to be using hugo, for my blog. The reason
I had to quit tumblr was due to missing syntax highlighting support. Moreover hugo is open
source and that itself is a great motivation for me to try it out. I will be moving all my
blogs to hugo, over the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How a programmer feels</title>
      <link>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/programmer_feels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 16:22:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/programmer_feels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a very good quality, every amazing programmer has. It’s their love towards programming or the whole technology, surrounding computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a programmer myself, I have come across situations, where it was very frustrating to debug. It may take days, even weeks to find the issue. But we never give up. It’s like a battle between bug and the programmer. And you know what, we have this ego, there is nothing we can’t accomplish. Something like this, goes in our minds &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Bug, you can’t hide from me for long. I am gonna get you soon”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Its the challenge, that makes it more fun and interesting. The degree of difficulty, is proportional to the degree of awesomeness, we feel solving it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally finding the bug, is liking finding a mythical creature. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Here you are, got you’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. That particular moment of realisation, is incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok 1 down, 5 to go….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to tap our natural instincts to succeed</title>
      <link>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/natural_instincts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 20:44:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://dineshs91.github.io/blog/post/natural_instincts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We human beings have a natural tendency of wanting more. Confused ? ok, let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many of us, still use the same phones that we first bought ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer will be None. The reason is, the human tendency i was talking about earlier.
We always want more/better with what we get or what we have. So now having understood the power of this instinct, we should figure out how we can use it to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only way to this, is to do what we really love, to do what we are really passionate about. A guy who is passionate about writing, never stops writing after one successful book or a passionate football player does not stop after one great match. They always grow and keep getting better at what they do. This is because of the natural human tendency, and it is very powerful. Nothing can stop it. People have died because of it, chasing their dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the only way, to make use of that power within ourselves, is to find what we truly love and what we want to do, for the rest of our lives. And the day we find our true passion, there would be no stopping us and we will become the pioneers of that field.
No matter how much time it would take, we should keep looking for it, hoping that one day we will find what we really want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started looking for it and so should you. Never give up. We are born for it and we are meant to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>